《古墓丽影》
停!
Stop!
嗨
Hey, y'all
混帐!
You bugger!
叫你不要用真枪实弹
Not live rounds, Lara.
瞧它现在多痛苦
He's in real pain right now.
我刚刚把它改装好，你这样真是要命
This is a major remodel.This is a disaster.
有程序命令它在锯掉我脑袋前停止吗？
Was it programmed to stop before it took my head off?
那倒是…没有
Ah, well, that would be a no.
是你说要有挑战性，所以…
But you said make it more challenging, so...
要真枪实弹
Hence, the live fiire.
又完成了
Hmm, live rounds again.
可怜的孩子
Poor Simon.
她对你做了什么?
What has she done to you?
太有趣了
Very funny.
你得打扮成淑女
I'm only trying to turn you into a lady.
淑女应该庄重些
And a lady should be modest.
对，庄重的应该是淑女
Yes, a lady should be modest.
(意大利 威尼斯)
兄弟姐妹们…
Brothers and sisters...
今天是五月十五日…
today is the 15th of May...
今天是九星一线的第一天…
the fiirst day of the planetary alignment...
可我们至今没能查到那把钥匙的下落
and we are still no nearer to discovering the location of the key.
看来…
It seems...
我们快要没时间了
we are running out of time.
真是让人无法忍受
This is not acceptable.
鲍威尔先生，请你给我们解释一下
Mr. Powell,your explanation for this, please?
我没法解释.也不想找借口
I have no explanation.Certainly no excuses.
我只想再一次恭敬的提醒委员会…
Except to once again，respectfully remind the council...
我们工作所依据的线索是基于古老的宇宙模型…
that we are working from clues based on ancient cosmological models...
其理论要早于亚里斯多德
predating Aristotle.
我们差不多已准备就绪了
But I'm happy to announce that we're almost ready.
而且我有极大的信心…
And I am supremely confiident...
在九星一线之时我们能得到答案
that we will have our answer in time for the relevant planetary alignment.
那么，到时候我们会有把钥匙…
So, we will have possession of the key in...
就是一星期之后
one week.
对，没错…一星期
Yes, indeed... one week.
这是好消息，鲍威尔先生，可要记住…
This is good news, Mr. Powell,but remember...
我们只有那唯一的一次机会…
we have only a single opportunity...
去找回那一分为二的三角
to retrieve the two halves of the triangle.
如果我们失败了…
And if we fail...
那么我们就得再等上五千年
we must wait another 5,000 years.
你那里我不了解，可我所答应的时间…
I don't know about you,but that's more time...
还绰绰有余
than I am prepared to commit to this enterprise.
我们没有问题
We shall be ready.
相信我们
Trust me.
我们没...没准备好，是吗？ 好了
We're not...We're not ready, are we? No
早上好，劳拉.多美的早晨!
Good morning, Lara. And what a beautiful morning it is.
该开始干活了
Back to work, I'm afraid.
冒险的时刻到了
It's adventure time.
又是埃及
Egypt again.
那儿只有金字塔和沙子
It's nothing but pyramids and sand.
我知道.遍地都是...无孔不入
I know.Gets everywhere... in the cracks.
西班牙大帆船？
Spanish galleon?
知道今天几号，荷里？
Do you know what day it is, Hillary?
知道，当然知道
Yes, of course.
15号
The 15th.
这可不是个好日子
And that is never a good day.
我想你，爸爸
I miss you, Daddy.
真希望能把被偷去的时间抢回来
I wish we could get back the time that was stolen from us.
我父亲看到这个一定会高兴的
My father would love to have seen this.
今晚冥王星，海王星，天王星将成一直线
Tonight Pluto and Neptune align with Uranus.
这是九星一线的第一阶段…
It's the fiirst stage of the alignment of all nine planets...
九星一线的高潮是日全蚀
culminating in a full solar eclipse.
这要五千年才发生一次
It only happens once every 5,000 years.
日全蚀是什么时候？
When is the eclipse?
还有一星期
One week from today.
可在那之前还有许多可以看到的东西
But there is plenty to look out for until then.
不可思议
Incredible.
我希望你能记得她.她是多么的爱你
I wish you could remember her. She loved you so much.
妈妈!
Mummy!
我也希望我能记得她
I wish I could remember her too.
我还有你，爸爸
I still have you, Daddy.
对，没错
Yes, you do.
九星一线的景象得靠那三角发挥作用…
The exact alignment of the planets necessary to activate the triangle...
这种景象五千年才会出现一次
only occurs once every 5,000 years.
时间足够了，足以等到…
But that will prove to be just long enough...
我们的小劳拉长大成人…
for little Lara Croft to grow up...
去得到那神光三角
and to find it.
布莱斯!
Bryce!
嗨，伙计们
Hello, fellas.
怎么了？ 布莱斯!
How's business?  Bryce!
好了，好了.我来了.我来了
Okay, okay.I'm coming. I'm coming.
我们有83间房.你就不能住屋子里吗？
We have 83 rooms.Why can't you live in the house?
我这个人爱自由
Well, I'm a free spirit, me.
好了
Right.
什么味儿？
What's that smell?
五点了，我们走
5:00 a.m. Let's go
但愿是好事
This had better be good.
是一只钟
It's a clock.
昨晚找到的.它老滴嗒响
I found it last night.It was ticking.
肯定是一只滴嗒钟
Must be one of them ticking clocks, eh?
它被藏在一间秘室里
It was hidden in a secret room.
正经点
Don't start.
劳拉，这真是只钟. 滴嗒滴嗒报时.可时间不对
Lara, it's a clock. It ticks. It tells the time. It's wrong.
昨晚九星一线开始…
It started ticking...
它也开始滴嗒了
last night during the fiirst stage of the alignment.
好吧，我要杯咖啡
Well, gonna need some coffee.
好，进去瞧瞧
Okay, in we go.
看起来很普通
Looks pretty ordinary to me.
再接着看
Well, keep looking.
您的咖啡，先生.脱咖啡因加脱脂牛奶
Your coffee, sir.Decaf latte with nonfat milk.
棒极了，热气腾腾的
Oh, champion. Steaming sump oil.
等等.你干了什么？
Wait. What did you do?
- 我干了什么了？ - 这是什么？
- I don't know. What did I do?  - Where is that?
不知道.我的手刚放开探头
I don't know. I just took my hand off the fiiber optics.
那是什么？
What is that?
- 混帐! - 混帐
- Oh, bugger! - Bugger.
三号螺丝到第四象限
Screw 13 to quadrant four.
- 四号螺丝到第三象限. - 喔，得了吧
- Screw 14 to quadrant three. - Oh, please.
这是我的图纸，不会弄错从哪里取
It's my map, so I know where they all came from.
这是一个伪装
It's camouflage.
好吧
Okay.
藏在里面了
Hidden within.
是什么？
What is that?
万世神眼
The All Seeing Eye.
第121件，路易十五镶金立架座钟
Lot 121, a Louis XV Ormolu mounted bracket clock.
在我的左边，一百八十万英镑
Showing on my left,1,800,000 pounds.
一百八十万，谢谢.一百八十万英镑
1,800,000. Thank you. One million eight. 1,900,000.
二百万.现在是二百万英镑
Two million pounds.Two million pounds now.
二百一十万.现在二百一十万英镑.二百一十万英镑
2,100,000. 2,100,000 now.2,100,000 pounds.
还有高过二百一十万英镑的吗？
Any advance on 2,100,000 pounds?
还有吗？二百一十万.二百二十万英镑.谢谢，先生
Any more? Two million one.2,200,000. Thank you, sir.
现在是二百二十万英镑
2,200,000 pounds now.
二百二十万英镑.二百三十万英镑
At 2,200,000.2,300,000.
二百三十.二百四十万英镑
Two million three.2,400,000.
女士叫价，现在是二百四十万英镑
Lady's bid, 2,400,000 pounds.2,400,000.
你呢，先生？二百五十万？不是
Against you, sir.Two million fiive? No.
二百四十万英镑，女士叫价.二百五十万英镑
2,400,000 pounds, then. Lady's bid at two million four. 2,500,000.
又有了新价，现在是二百五十万英镑
In a new place at 2,500,000 pounds.
还有吗？现在是二百五十万英镑
Any more at 2,500,000 pounds?
成交
Sold.
劳拉，亲爱的
Lara, my dear.
- 威尔逊先生. - 去我的书房吧.那儿安静点
- Mr. Wilson. - Come to my study. I'll take that.
劳拉克拉夫特.我真没想到
Lara Croft. I don't believe it.
- 我一会就来. - 嗨
- I'll just be a minute. - Hi.
你还在假扮是个摄影记者？
You still pretending to be a photojournalist?
我觉得那很酷，还有份白天的工作…
You know, I think it's really cool that you still have a day job...
很显然，那只是装装样子
even though it's obviously just for show.
那么，艾历克斯，你还在假扮考古学家？
So, Alex, are you still pretending to be an archaeologist?
我们总得这么争吵吗？
Do we always have to fiight like this?
也许不需要
I mean, maybe we don't.
- 也许需要. - 为什么？
- Maybe we do. - Why?
- 你偷了我的祈祷文.  - 偷？偷？
- You stole my prayer wheels. - Stole? Stole?
偷了你的？那真可笑
From you? You know, that's funny. You know, it's...
它们可不能算你的私人物品
It's not like you ever really owned them or anything.
你是个盗墓的
Hey, you're the tomb raider.
威斯特先生，就等你了
Mr. West, we are ready for you.
看来你的客户们需要你
Oh, I think your clients need you.
去吧.拍卖会正等着你呢
Go ahead.You're wanted on the floor.
毕竟你说过一句:“生意归生意”
After all, as you said so memorably, "It's all just a business."
那就去做生意吧
Right? So go do business.
去吧
Go.
劳拉，这东西可是世间少有
Lara, this is a unique object.
只有一个圆盘在转
Only one of the dials is working.
会发光，就象是眼睛
It glows, like the eye, lesser.
可是好象越来越亮
But it seems to be getting brighter.
而且是在反方向转…
And it's also running backwards...
不象在准确报时，倒象是在倒计时
like it's not so much keeping time but counting down to something.
- 是啊. - 你看这后面
- Yes. - And look at the back.
象是有什么东西，就象是把钥匙
It's as though it fiits into something, almost like a key.
是啊.是啊
Yes. Yes, fascinating.
- 真是美妙绝伦. - 父亲说有块魔力三角…
- Incredibly beautiful.  - My father once told me...
上面刻着万世神眼
of a magical triangle stamped with the All Seeing Eye.
他说谁拥有它，谁就会有超凡的力量...
He said it gave its possessor extraordinary power...
控制时间的力量
the power to control time.
父亲管它叫神光三角.你听说过吗？
He called it the Triangle of Light. Have you heard of it?
不.没听说过
No. No, I haven't.
你父亲总是按自己的方式办事，很有主见
He always steered his own course,your father.
他很了不起
He was a great man.
你要不要来点葡萄酒？
Would you like some port?
- 味道可不错. - 不
- It's really very fiine. - No.
我没办法帮你，劳拉
I can't help you, Lara.
这个钟实在是一个迷
This clock truly is a mystery.
- 喂. - 劳拉？
- Hello. - Lara?
你好，我是威尔逊先生
Hello, it's Mr. Wilson.
是这样...那个钟的事…
Yes. Well, l...You see, I had a second thought...
我稍微想了一下
about that clock.
有个人也许可以帮你
There is a man who may be able to help you.
我给你他的号码.他的名字叫鲍威尔
I gave him your number.His name is Manfred Powell.
你可以去找他
You should see him.
谢谢，我会的
Thank you. I will.
再见，劳拉. 你保重
Good-bye, Lara. You take care.
谢谢
Thank you.
混帐
Bugger.
原谅我
Forgive me.
克拉夫特小姐
Lady Croft.
- 鲍威尔先生. - 哦，不，不，不
- Ah, Mr. Powell. - Oh, no, no, no. Good heavens, no.
实际上我是他的同事，匹姆斯先生
I'm actually his associate, Mr. Pimms.
- 匹姆斯先生？ - 对，就象是饮料的名字
- Mr. Pimms?  - Yeah, like the beverage.
对，她来了
Yeah, she's here.
鲍威尔先生干哪行的？
What does Mr. Powell do?
他是律师.我是他的顾问…
He's a lawyer.I'm his law clerk...
兼助理，最近才任命的，轻松工作而不单调
and fairly recent appointment,but enjoying it, all the varied work.
一个律师. 看不出来吗？
A lawyer. Isn't it obvious?
克拉夫特小姐，我很荣幸
Lady Croft, my pleasure.
鲍威尔皇家法律顾问 早上好
Manfred Powell, Q. C.  Good morning.
研究那些古代和神话的东西你很权威
I believe you are quite an authority on things ancient and mythological.
我不敢当
Well, I travel.
威尔逊先生说你是个出色的考古学家
No, no, Mr. Wilson said you were quite the archaeologist.
请
Please.
哦.他真可爱
Oh, he's very sweet.
他认识你父亲吧
He knew your father, I believe.
对，他们是好朋友
Yes, they were great friends.
我有幸见过你父亲一面，在威尼斯
I had the honor of meeting him myself once, in Venice.
听说他死了我很遗憾
I was so sorry to hear about his death.
这就是我说的钟
This is the clock I spoke of.
很有意思
Very interesting.
可惜你只带了照片
It's a shame you only brought photographs.
不过这钟实在是太神了
Nevertheless, it is fascinating.
- 是在九星一线第一阶段开始滴嗒的？ - 对
- You said it started ticking the night of the alignment. - Yes.
- 你说你是律师？ - 没错
- You said you were a lawyer? - Yes.
那么研究钟是你的业余爱好？
And the study of clocks is a hobby?
这是我的专长
This is an obsession.
我对这着了迷.我做律师常和古董打交道
Really my speciality. My practice centers around antiquities.
可我实在想不出…
But the origin of this clock...
这只钟的来源
completely eludes me.
我从未见过如此美丽的东西…
I think I've never seen anything quite so beautiful...
可我却对此一无所知
that I know so little about.
无知对我是种折磨
This is a pleasurable torment.
可是无知带给我乐趣
My ignorance amuses me.
“可是无知带给我乐趣.”
"My ignorance amuses me."
对，我发现你的无知倒是挺逗人的
Yes, well, I've always found your ignorance quite amusing.
可鲍威尔并不是无知
Powell, however, is not ignorant.
他在撒谎
He's a liar.
- 需要什么吗？ - 不.谢谢，荷里
- Anything you need? - No. Thank you, Hillary.
- 别睡的太晚了. - 不会
- Don't you stay up too late.  - I won't.
第一队，等待我的命令
Forward team, wait for my command.
就位，待命
In position awaiting your order.
杂种!
Bastards!
该死的!
Bloody hell!
射左面，射左面
On the left.On the left.
快点，宝贝!
Come on, Simon!
快点! 快！快!
Come on!Come on!Come on!
劳拉，劳拉，你在吗？快接!
Lara, Lara, are you there?Pick up!
劳拉，你听的见吗？你没事吧？
Lara, can you hear me?Are you okay?
我在装备室.他们要偷我的钟
I'm in the equipment room. They're stealing my bloody clock.
我知道.我看见了
I know. I saw them.
你做我的眼睛. 你有武器吗？
You have to be my eyes. Are you armed?
就算有吧
After a fashion, yes.
那好，有三个坏家伙
All right. Three bad guys.
第一个站在阿斯顿马丁车边
Number one standing by the Aston Martin.
好
Right.
太棒了!
Bingo!
- 下一个. - 好，第二个…
- Next. - Okay, number two...
蹲在麦克拉伦车边
crouched by the McLaren.
噢 混帐!
Oh, bugger!
你没事吧？没事，刚找到车钥匙
Are you okay?  I just found my car keys.
你完了，伙计.这手漂亮
You're done, mate.Nice one.
我想他们都跑了
I think they've all gone.
那钟不能落在他们手里
They got what they came for.
对不起了
Sorry about that.
没关系
That's fine.
喂？
Hello?
这儿到底发生了什么？
What the hell happened here?
- 早上好. - 劳拉克拉夫特小姐？
- Morning. - Lady Lara Croft?
你有东西给我？
Yes. You have something for me?
我今早起来，忽然发了通无名火
I woke up this morning, and I just hated everything.
是吗.谢谢
Right. Thanks.
谁是史崔宾，克莱夫和温特萨？
Who's Stribling, Clive and Winterset then?
- 听着象是一帮律师. - 你的眼睛真尖
- Sounds like a bunch of lawyers. - They are a bunch of lawyers.
- 好，我就闭嘴. - 你多管闲事
- Well, I'll shut my face again. - You are nosy.
才不是.我只是看这名字很怪
I'm not nosy.I just saw the name.
才问她这些人是谁的
It was a funny name.I just asked her what the name was.
是我父亲
It's from my father.
是他死之前写的…
It was written before he died...
并按照他的吩咐今天送到
and delivered today as per his instructions.
真怪啊! 神圣
Blimey! Holy sh...
看一粒沙中的世界…
"To see a world in a grain of sand...
一朵野花中的天堂…
and a heaven in a wild flower...
把无限握于掌中…
hold infiinity in the palm of your hand...
把永恒握于瞬间
and eternity in an hour."
是威廉布莱克的诗
William Blake.
万世神眼
The All Seeing Eye.
我亲爱的女儿…
My darling daughter...
我料到你能领悟出来
I knew you'd figure this out.
你看到这封信，意味着我已经不在了…
If you are reading this letter, I am no longer with you...
我想你…
and I miss you...
我永远爱你，永远
and love you always and forever.
这意味着我失败了…
It also means I have failed...
必须把这重担交给你
and must place an awful burden on your shoulders.
劳拉，我想你已经找到了被我藏起来的钟
Lara, by now I am sure you will have discovered the clock I concealed.
钟就是一把钥匙，劳拉
The clock is the key, Lara.
用这钟就可以打开藏着那三角的地方
It will unlock the hiding place of two pieces of a sacred icon.
那三角就是你小时候我所说的魔力三角
This is the magical triangle I told you about when you were little.
神光三角.这可不是童话故事里的
The Triangle of Light.But it is no bedtime story.
那是由陨石坑里发现的金属锻造的…
The triangle was forged from metal found in the crater of a meteor...
那陨石是上个九星一线时…
that had fallen to Earth at the exact moment...
跌落到地球上的
of the previous alignment of the nine planets.
光的子民在陨石坑上建了座大城市…
The people of the light built a great city in this crater...
在那里朝拜这三角，它能控制时间
where they worshipped the triangle for its ability to control time.
拥有它的人会具有一股力量，以行善或是作恶
It gave its possessor a power that could be used for good or great evil.
因为滥用这力量而毁灭了这城市
An abuse of this power led to the destruction of the city.
为了保证不再有人能掌握这力量…
To be sure no man would ever again wield this power...
他们把三角劈成了两半…
they split the triangle into two pieces...
并把他们藏在地球相对的两端
and hid them at opposite ends of the Earth.
劳拉，记得那种茉莉花吗？
Lara, do you remember thejasmine that only grows in one temple...
那只长在东方一个古老国家的一个寺庙里
along the ancient Khmer trail in Cambodia?
找到它就能找到…
Find that and you will have found the entrance...
闪光之墓的入口…
to the Tomb of the Dancing Light...
第一半三角就藏在那里
where the first half of the triangle is hidden.
九星一线第二阶段开始之前…
You must be there at the exact moment...
你必须在那儿
of the second phase of the planetary alignment.
你得赶快.时间很紧
You must hurry.You have very little time.
当九大行星连成一条直线时…
And as the planets move into alignment...
世界就会很危险…
the world will be in great danger...
那个叫光照先知的秘会社...
for the secret society known as the Illuminati...
这帮邪恶，阴险的人…
devious, dangerous men...
要实现一个古老的预言…
who seek to fulfill an ancient prophecy...
方法就是把两半三角拼起来…
by reuniting the two halves...
获取惊人的可怕力量
and attaining the triangle's awesome and terrible powers.
你必须不惜一切去阻止
This you must prevent at all costs.
所以，劳拉，我期待你去完成我的工作…
So, Lara, I am asking you to complete my work...
去找到那两半三角，然后毁了它们
to find and destroy both halves of the triangle.
你怎么可能赶的那么远去把钟夺回来？只有十五个小时了
How are you going to get to Cambodia and get the clock back in 15 hours?
我会叫人帮忙
I'll be calling in a favor.
- 怎么帮？ - 这可是个秘密
- What kind of favor? - Well, that is a secret.
如果告诉你，我就得杀了你
If I told you,I'd have to kill you.
克拉夫特小姐，到达目标了吗？
Lady Croft, are you on target? Over.
到达目标.谢谢，伙计们.通话完毕
Right on target.Thank you, boys. Over and out.
就料到你会在这儿
How predictable.
艾历克斯威斯特
Alex West.
你到这儿来干什么？
What are you doing here?
离九星一线第二阶段还有72分钟
We have 72 minutes to the next alignment.
得干的再快点
We have to work faster.
再加把劲!
Come on, guys!
再加把劲!快点拉!
Come on, guys! Come on. Pull!
拉!
Pull! It's coming!
很好
Good.
那么，看见克拉夫特小姐了吗？
So, any sign of Lady Croft?
还没有
Not yet.
别把她看的太高.她虽然很棒…
Lara's overrated.She's good, don't get me wrong...
但她只是为了荣耀…
but she's in it for the glory...
而我是为了钱
whereas I'm in it for the money.
该相信幸运
Fortunately.
- 钻进野兽的肚子. - 钻出魔鬼的屁眼
- Into the belly of the beast. - And out of the demon's ass.
茉莉花
Jasmine.
记住，我们要找的不仅藏在空间…
Remember, what we are looking for is hidden not only in space...
还藏在时间里
but also in time.
钟就是钥匙
The clock is the key.
我的天哪
My God.
当铁重归石头的怀抱…
"Return the iron to the stone's embrace...
天轮会转动
the wheel of heaven will turn.
水会将光化解出来…
Exhume the light from its watery grave...
你会获得超凡的力量…
to receive the gift of heaven...
可你会受到诅咒
as you are condemned to the depths of hell."
好啊.要知道碰这儿的东西就会有杀身之祸
Right. Pretty much touch anything and you get your head chopped off.
还有两分钟.威斯特先生
We have two minutes, Mr. West.
你是盗墓的.想想办法
You're the tomb raider.Figure it out.
光阴似箭
Tempus fugit.
对，“时光飞逝.”
Yes, "time flies."
那些剑!
It's the swords!
来吧，上来.来帮我个忙
Come on, guys. Get up here.Give me a hand here.
对，来吧
That's it. Come on.Coming down.
把它们全拿下来
I want them all down.
然后把它们搬过梯子去
Take them, carry them across the ladders.
动作要快
Let's hustle.
好，现在把剑插到那些洞里去
All right. Now slide them into the slots over there.
第二阶段开始的那一刻， 就要把钟放在这儿
We place the clock here at the exact moment of alignment.
快点.加油!动作快!
Come on. Let's go! Move it!
太慢了，娘们们 动作快
Too slow, ladies, too slow.Come on.
成了.倒计时
That's it. Count it down.
- 计时得精准. - 那可没问题
- The timing needs to be exact. - No shit.
还有60秒
Sixty seconds to go.
59，58…
59, 58...
57，56…
57, 56...
55，54…
55, 54...
53，52，51…
53, 52, 51...
还有五十秒
fiifty seconds.
别开枪!都停下!
Cease fire! Hold your fiire!
- 接着计时. - 你是大错特错了!
- Keep counting. - You're making a big mistake!
41，40…
41, 40...
39，38…
39, 38...
来旅行的？
Tourist visa?
- 不，是来工作的. - 克拉夫特小姐，你猜…
- No, I'm working. - Lady Croft, tell me...
我为什么会放你一条生路？
is there a good reason why I kept you alive?
当然，真正的眼睛不在这儿
Yes. That is not the true eye.
- 就是这个眼睛. - 不是，真不是
- This is the true eye. - It's not, actually.
它只是个镜像
It's a mirror image.
克拉夫特小姐，我认为你想把我的宝贝骗走
Miss Croft I think you're trying to cheat me out of my little ray of sunshine.
我现在干嘛要骗走你的东西？
Why would I try and cheat you out of anything now?
我要你找到那三角，那样我就能偷走
I need you to get the piece so I can steal it from you later.
别唬我了.朱列斯，你记住...
You're bluffiing.Julius, make a mental note...
她要敢偷，你就格杀勿论
Dill Miss Croft if she attempts any such thing.
遵命，鲍威尔先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Powell.
要不听我的，要不等到下次九星一线再来…
We can do it my way, or we can come back in time for the next alignment...
到那个时候你再来杀我
and you are welcome to try and kill me then.
不过那可得再过五千年
In, oh, say another 5,000 years.
12，11…
12, 11...
十…
ten...
九，八…
nine, eight...
七，六，五…
seven, six, fiive...
四，三…
four, three...
二，一…
two, one...
零
zero.
劳拉没说错
I guess she was right.
木头得刺穿那缸
The log must pierce the urn.
快点!
Come on!
开始慢下来了.看来没法成功
It's slowing down. It's never gonna make it.
神光，神火和神水
Pure light, fiire and water.
去拿那钟
Get the clock.
知道了
Got it.
站着别动!
Hold it right there!
劳拉，快交出来
Give it up.
你想对我开枪吗，艾历克斯？
Are you going to shoot me, Alex?
请问哪里可以打长途电话？
我的电话湿了
My phone is wet.
喂？
Yes?
克拉夫特小姐，你好吗？
Lady Croft, how are you?
还活着
Alive.
活蹦乱跳的？
And kicking, I hope.
- 对，你呢？  - 简直好极了
- And you? - Superlative.
好了，言归正传.我那半三角在你那儿
Of course, I digress.You have my half of the triangle.
而我父亲的钟在你那儿
And you have my father's clock.
我说亲爱的，我们这会儿谁也缺不了谁
Listen, my dear. Without each other we are quite useless at this point.
我们该重新认识形势
We should reevaluate our positions.
就认了吧，我们俩得合作
Like it or not,you and I are in business together.
生意伙伴得见面
We should have a business meeting.
你是说你很想再找个机会杀我？
You mean you'd love to have another opportunity to try and kill me.
这多难听
Oh, that's harsh.
不过也许.等着瞧
But perhaps.Wait and see.
去威尼斯吧.别怕一路辛苦
Come to Venice,Via Dolorosa.
好极了，那么再见
Wonderful. Bye then.
重点儿
Harder.
它来了，大家躲起来
Here it comes. Hide, everybody.
小心.那是机器
Look out.It's some sort of machine.
布莱斯，是我
Bryce, it's me.
- 喂？ - 我是劳拉.找到了庙
- Hello? - It's Lara. I found the temple.
- 碰见了鲍威尔先生. - 抢回那钟了吗？
- Ran into Mr. Powell. - Did you get the clock?
没有，可拿到了第一半三角
No, but I got the fiirst piece.
噢.这太棒了
Oh, beautiful, smashing.
看来我们和鲍威尔势均力敌
Seems I'm level pegging with Mr. Powell.
- 可他不是要杀你吗？ - 不，傻瓜
- Won't he just want to kill you now? - No, silly.
他需要把我的那半三角搞到手
His problem is that he needs the piece that I have.
在那之前，我是他生意伙伴
Until then,I'm his new best friend.
可是另一半呢？离九星一线最后阶段…
What about the other half?The final alignment...
还有66小时53分钟，可我们还不知道…
is in 66 hours and 53 minutes, and we've still got no idea...
另一半藏在哪里
where the second piece is hidden.
他会告诉我那另一半会藏在哪里
He's going to tell me where the second piece is.
- 他会吗？ - 相信我，布莱斯.收拾一下，去威尼斯.
- He will? - Bryce, trust me. Pack for Venice.
去哪儿？喂？劳拉？
Pack for where? Hello? Lara?
那么再见
Bye then.
喝了它
Drink.
休息
Rest.
心无邪念方能息
There's no rest for the wicked.
你得到了你想要的东西？
You got what you came for?
是的，没错
I did, yes.
不好，对这个世界不好
Too bad. Bad for the world.
这世界很安全
The world is safe now.
有你在会更安全的
Little bit safer,perhaps...
你会继续下去
because you will go on.
你父亲说过.你从不放弃
Your father said you will never give up.
我父亲？你认识我父亲？
My father? You knew my father?
现在，喝吧，把茶喝完
Now, drink. Finish your tea.
虽然很难喝，可是对你有好处
It tastes quite bad,but it is good for you.
瞧？
See?
晚上好
Good evening.
你是光照先知会社的人
You're with the Illuminati.
你说什么？
Beg your pardon?
没这回事.那是个童话故事
There's no such thing.It's just a bedtime story.
光照先知…
Illuminati...
光的子民
The people of the light.
我的三角带来了吗？
Have you brought my triangle?
不，你当然不会带来.你一定把它藏好了
No, of course you haven't.You've hidden it somewhere.
好吧，你可以藏着那半三角…
You can keep the triangle you have...
而我藏着你父亲的钟，我们可以做搭档
and I will keep your father's clock, and we can be partners.
谁坐这儿？
Who sits here?
我们能一起拿到另一半...
We can be partners and go for the big prize...
然后拼出神光三角
the Triangle of Light.
对，可谁坐在这儿？
Yes, but who sits here?
不可思议的梦，巨大的力量
It's an incredible dream,an aesome poer.
能纠正无数的错误
It could set right so many rongs.
我看坐这儿的不会是你
I don't think you sit here,do you?
我坐这儿…
I sit here...
可以说是坐在神的右手
on God's right hand,as it were.
其实…
In fact...
现在我坐的地方，正是以前你父亲坐的位置
I now sit exactly where your father sat.
你撒谎
You're lying.
不，他曾指导过我
No, he mentored me in the order.
那是莫大的荣幸
It was truly an honor.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我父亲不是光照先知的人
My father was not with the Illuminati.
- 他没和我说过. - 他的秘密多着呢
- He would have told me. - He had a great many secrets.
他从不瞒我
Not from me.
他尤其要瞒你
Especially from you.
我知道你要什么，劳拉
I know what you want, Lara.
这我可怀疑
Oh, I doubt it.
你要和你父亲团聚…
Another life with your father...
一切重新来过
a second chance.
我完全有能力
It'll be within my power to give.
拥有那三角，就拥有了…
The triangle gives its possessor...
神的力量...
the power of God...
能穿梭于时空之中，改变过去的事情
to move back and forth through time, undo the past.
你帮我，就能得到你想要的...
Help me, and you will get what I know you want...
使你父亲回到你身边
to have your father returned to you.
也许我给了你那半三角之后…
And how do I know once I gave you that piece...
你就会想法杀了我
that you wouldn't then just try to kill me?
杀你还不容易吗...
Would it make it easier for you...
或者我现在杀了你？
on more familiar ground...if I killed you now?
你能考虑下吗？
Will you reconsider?
- 你好，艾历克斯. - 你一定认为我是个…
- Hello, Alex. - I suppose you think...
贪婪，无耻的叛徒…
I'm a greedy, unscrupulous sellout...
- 为了钱什么都可以干. - 算你说对了
- and do about anything for money. - Yes, that's right.
说我为钱倒是不错
Well, the money bit's true,I guess.
是吗，艾历克斯？
Is it, Alex?
如果你出卖我，也许我们再也做不成朋友
If you cross me, we may not be able to remain friends.
真是幸会
Always a pleasure.
真不该洗热水澡
Now for a cold shower.
我们有大麻烦了
I think we're in big trouble.
给我拿着 谢谢
Hold this, will you? Thank you.
他们以为我们拿到了克拉夫特小姐的那半三角
They already think we have Lady Croft's piece of the triangle.
他们以为那在你手上的这个盒子里
Yes. They think it's in that box you're carrying right now.
有吗？
Is it?
你为什么不担心担心别的什么?
Why don't you worry about something else?
盒子里当然没有
Of course it's not.
我不明白.我们有多少成功机会？
I don't understand. What chance of success do we have without it?
零.动动脑子
Zero. Don't dwell on it.
可是…
But...
真是又惊又喜啊
What a nice surprise.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了，又要出发拯救宇宙了？
Now, time to save the universe again then, is it?
那是当然
Absolutely.
真有必要带这女人一起去？
Are we sure she's really necessary?
带一个盗墓的管用.带两个，更好
Well, one tomb raider is good. Two, better.
我的屁股又发麻了，是左边那半
Me bum's gone to sleep again, all down the left cheek.
是吗？有趣
Really? That's fascinating.
- 还要多久？ - 几个小时
- How much longer? - A few hours.
最后一小时我们得走着去
We have to take the last hour over land.
直升机不能飞进那废墟城
Helicopters won't fly near the ruined city.
是死亡地带
It's a dead zone.
(俄罗斯 西伯利亚)
我们要所有的狗
We take all doggies.
我有大把的美金
Much-o U.S. Greenback.
要所有的狗
All doggies.
- 你们这是要去冰湖吗？ - 对
- 去那大坑？ - 对，去那陨石坑
别去，太冒险了. 就为了再见到他
再见到谁？
你的父亲
欢迎来死亡地带
Welcome to the dead zone.
这个地方简直是个冰窟窿
It's not a country. It's an ice cube!
来吧!
Come on!
好了，走吧
All right. Let's go.
去，上!
Go on, get it!
天哪
Holy shit.
是时间风暴.时间被打破了
It's a time storm. Time is broken here.
我们得找到神眼!全都上!赶快!
We must fiind the eye! All of you! Hurry!
快没时间了!快!快上!
We're running out of time! Hurry! Hurry!
开始了
It's begun.
另一半一定在那太阳上
Fifty bucks says the piece is inside the sun.
你们都给我快点.日蚀很快就会结束了!
For God's sake, hurry! The eclipse will be over in a few minutes!
把钟给我.我知道该怎么办
Give me the clock.I know what to do.
拿到那一半了吗？
Has she got the piece?
我们现在…
We will now...
将让这两半合二为一…\r}
unite these two parts...
把过去和现在合起来
the past and the present.
我们，光照先知会社…
At last,we of the Illuminati...
将控制时间，并履行我们曾对我们祖先许下的…
will control time and fulfiill the sacred promise...
神圣诺言
to our ancestors.
很快，整个世界都将... 废话太多了
Soon, the entire world will bow... Enough of this twaddle.
快走!快走!
Come on! Come on!
不象你希望的那样吧？
Not quite what you hoped for, Mr. Powell?
这事我有种直觉
I have a gut instinct about this.
毕竟，你是天才的女儿
After all, you are the daughter of a genius.
让我就来试一下
Let me test my theory.
你只能放弃他了.他不再冒泡了
You had to let him go.No more bubbles.
你教我怎么用那三角…
You show me how to complete the triangle...
就能改变他的命运
we can change his fate.
我得到神的力量，把时间逆转
If you deliver me the power of God,I will spare him.
他就能获得新生
It's only a little trip back in time.
我想你应该能想出办法来解决这问题
But I'm pretty sure you've fiigured out the answer to the problem.
至于你想见到你父亲
And then, of course, there's the loss of your father.
我也能办到
I can change that.
那你做好准备
You'd better be ready for this.
- 把激光瞄准器给我. - 快给她
- Unhook your laser sight. - Do it.
“看一粒沙中的世界.”
"To see a world in a grain of sand."
爸爸？
Daddy?
这是真的吗？
Is this real?
是时空交错…
It is a crossing...
我的过去和你的现在
of my past and your present.
为什么不告诉我光照先知的事？
Why did you not tell me about the Illuminati?
当时你还小
You were only a child.
你可以写在日记里
You could have written in your journals.
- 可你却一次都没提过. - 我急于告诉你一切
- You never mentioned it... not once. - I burst to tell you everything.
可当时我要和他们周旋…
But in the fiierceness of my own battles...
所以只能告诉这些能启发你…
I strove to tell you only that which would inspire you...
并保你安全的事
and keep you safe.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
爸爸，我想你
But I've missed you.
我也想你
And I have missed you.
我知道你为什么来…
I know why you came here...
为什么集聚光的力量...可你不能这么做
why you took the power of the light... but this must not happen.
为什么？这力量用一次也不行吗？
Why? Why can't we use the power just this once?
你为什么不能留下？
Why can't you stay?
我们不能改变时间
We can't change time.
可你我的时间被偷走了…
But time was stolen from us...
这不公平
and it's not fair.
对，是不公平
No, it's not fair.
可现在你偷了时间…
But you have stolen time itself...
你必须还回去
and you must give it back.
你得毁了那三角
You must destroy the triangle.
我觉得很孤独
Suddenly I feel so alone.
你不孤独. 我会陪着你，永远陪着你
You're never alone. I am with you always, just as I've always been.
我们撤!
Move out!
等等!
Wait!
你父亲背叛了我们…
Your father begged for his life...
当他被抓的时候，跪下请求饶命
when we caught him betraying us.
他苦苦求饶，象个孩子
He pleaded like a baby.
投降吧
Surrender.
绝不
Never.
他好象最关心的是不让我拿走这个
He seemed particularly concerned that I shouldn't take this.
劳拉，不! 那儿快要塌了!
Lara, no!The place is coming down!
- 这样很愚蠢! - 带他们先走
- This is insane! - Get them out of here.
你快点啊
You just hurry.
放回去…
There you go...
完好无损
safe and sound.
不用枪
No guns.
我的上帝啊!
Oh, my God!
安静
Quiet.
怎么了？
What?